<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>docker on gruchalski.com</title>
    <link>https://gruchalski.com/tags/docker/</link>
    <description>Recent content in docker on gruchalski.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://gruchalski.com/tags/docker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Launching Alpine Linux on Firecracker like a boss</title>
      <link>https://gruchalski.com/posts/2021-02-13-launching-alpine-linux-on-firecracker-like-a-boss/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gruchalski.com/posts/2021-02-13-launching-alpine-linux-on-firecracker-like-a-boss/</guid>
      <description>The quest to launch an ETCD cluster on Firecracker starts here.
In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m describing how I&amp;rsquo;ve built my initial Alpine 3.13 VMM with OpenSSH and a dedicated sudoer user. In AWS, when one launches a Ubuntu instance, one can access it via ssh ubuntu@&amp;lt;address&amp;gt;, a CentOS VM is ssh centos@&amp;lt;address&amp;gt;. At the end of this write up, I&amp;rsquo;ll have ssh alpine@&amp;lt;address&amp;gt;. This VMM will have access to the outside world so I can install additional software and even ping the BBC!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keycloak With Docker Compose</title>
      <link>https://gruchalski.com/posts/2020-09-03-keycloak-with-docker-compose/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gruchalski.com/posts/2020-09-03-keycloak-with-docker-compose/</guid>
      <description>Keycloak is an open source Identity and Access Management System developed as a JBoss community project under the stewardship of Red Hat. Keycloak makes it is easy to secure apps and services written in many technologies using a large number client libraries.
Out of the box, we get things like Single Sign-On, Identity Brokering and Social Login, User Federation and Authorization Services.
With little to no code, we can give users of our apps the ability to sign in with Identity Providers like GitHub, Twitter or Google.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Spark on Mesos with Docker bridge networking</title>
      <link>https://gruchalski.com/posts/2015-11-23-apache-spark-on-mesos-with-docker-bridge-networking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gruchalski.com/posts/2015-11-23-apache-spark-on-mesos-with-docker-bridge-networking/</guid>
      <description>About two weeks ago, Virdata released a set of patches for Apache Spark enabling Spark to work on Mesos with Docker bridge networking. We are using these in production for our multi tenant Spark environment.
SPARK-11638: Spark patches All patches for all components described below are available in Spark JIRA. We&amp;rsquo;ve released patches for all versions of Spark available at the time of creating them - from 1.4.0 to 1.5.2. We have also released patches for Akka 2.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>